我叫梅林达·戈登
My name is Melinda Gordon.
刚结婚  刚搬来这个小镇
I just got married, just moved to a small town,
刚开了间古董店
just opened up an antique shop.
我也许和你相似
I might be just like you.
但当我还是小姑娘时
Except from the time that I was a little girl,
我就能同亡者交流
I knew that I could talk to the dead.
没事的  亲爱的
It's all right, honey.
祖母称他们为地缚灵
Earthbound spirits, my grandmother called them,
他们在人间滞留
the ones who have not crossed over
是因为他们有未了的心愿
because they have unfinished business with the living.
他们找我帮忙
And they come to me for help.
讲述我的故事  就是讲述他们的故事
To tell you my story, I have to tell you theirs.
救命
Help me!
谢天谢地你终于回来了
Thank God you're home.
这电影一个人看太恐怖了
This is not the kind of movie you wanna watch alone.
等等  这电影你看过
Wait. You've seen this before.
怎么还害怕
How is it still scary?
不知道  就是害怕
I don't know. It just is.
你还好吧
You okay?
不怎么好
I had a hard day.
但现在没事了
I'm fine now.
能抓着我的手陪我一起看吗
Will you hold my hand and watch this with me?
行  那我先洗个澡
Sure. I should hop in the shower first.
好的  快点
Okay. Hurry up.
你有没有过这种感觉
You ever have one of those days
好几天都怪怪的
where everything just feels weird?
别进去  为什么
Don't go in there. I mean, why?
为什么要那样做
Why do you do that?
就好像
You know, it's like I'm...
好像戴错了眼镜
Like I'm wearing the wrong pair of glasses or something.
怪就怪在我从不戴眼镜
Which is weird since I don't wear glasses.
开灯啊  白痴
Turn the lights on, bimbo!
怎么了
What?
吉姆
Jim?
没事
No, I'm fine.
我昨天修过水管
It's just the plumbing job I did yesterday.
可能铁锈跑进管子了
Must've knocked some rust into the pipes.
我忘记跟你说了  对不起
Oh, I should've told you. I'm sorry.
还洗了脸  真恶心
Washing my face? Gross.
怎么了
What's the matter?
没事  我去关水阀
Nothing, I'm just gonna lock up.
你看电影  我很快回来
Watch the movie. I'll be right back.
鬼语者  第一季  第8集
白鸽展翅
鲍比
Bobby!
是  救出来了
Yeah, I got it.
可能吸入过多烟雾了
It looks like smoke-induced asthma.
昏迷  呼吸微弱
All closed up. Agonal respiration.
氧气罩  支气管舒张剂
Let's get a paediatric mask, start an albuterol treatment.
快点  给我氧气罩
Come on, get that mask.
血压  90/140
BP 140 over 90.
有烧伤吗
Do you see any burns?
血压在降
Blood pressure is dropping.
吉姆  吉姆
Oh, Jim. Hey, Jim.
吉姆  血压还在降  她快不行了
Jim, BP's dropping. We're losing her.
要救活她
We're not losing her.
-快点  伙计  -是  快点
- Come on, man! - Yeah. Come on.
一定要救活她  呼吸
We're not losing her. Breathe.
来吧
Let's go.
好了  呼吸稳定了
Okay. Respiration's stabilising.
-她缓过来了  -带她走吧
- She's coming back. - Take her out.
你确定没事吗
You sure you're okay?
没事
I'm all right.
-好  带她离开  -送上车
- Okay, let's take her in. - Just take her up.
你说话了吗
Did you say something?
我  没有  我遇上
Me? No. I ran into...
你是不是告诉我  对不起
Do you tell me... Sorry.
-你说  -不  你说吧
- Go ahead. - No. You.
我告诉你什么
Do I tell you...
每当你看到鬼魂
Do you always tell me,
都会告诉我吗
you know, when you see spirits,
还是有太多鬼魂
or are there so many of them,
你没告诉我
you don't even mention it?
没告诉你
Door number two.
我只是
I just...
你是怎么应付的
I don't know how you deal with that.
接受他们  继续生活
I just factor it in, move on.
否则我会疯的
I guess I'd go crazy if I didn't.
现在有鬼吗
Is there someone here now?
没有
No.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
吉姆  你怎么了
Jim, what's going on?
你最近总是怪怪的
You've been acting really weird lately.
有什么烦心事吗
Is something bothering you?
我不知道是不是
Okay. I don't know if it's
因为和你在一起
just being with you, you know,
而受到你的影响
if it's rubbing off on me or something,
最近我总是有一些感觉
but lately I've been having these feelings.
什么感觉
What kind of feelings?
像被监视着
Like I'm being watched.
感觉一来  我就变得
And when it happens, I'm just
焦虑不安
flooded with this sense of anxiety
甚至是绝望
or, I don't know, with despair or something.
我好像处在一种
And it's like I'm in the presence of just...
濒临疯狂的状态
Talk about going crazy.
为什么  发生过什么事吗
Why, has something already happened?
可能只是紧张过度  我没事
You know, it's probably just nerves. I'm fine.
-还要吗  -不用
- Do you want some more? - No.
好的
All right.
他看上去像变了个人
He just seems so different.
怎么说
Different how?
心不在焉  闷闷不乐
Distracted. Moody.
也许是感情淡化了
Maybe the romance is fading.
不是吧
Are you serious?
吉姆那么爱你
Jim is nuts over you.
从冥王星上都能感受到爱意
You can feel the chemistry from, like, Pluto.
那是怎么回事
Then what's wrong?
不好意思  这个
Excuse me, but this...
梅格斯
Migs?
亚历西斯
Alexis.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我住这儿
I live here.
太意外了
Well, this is incredible.
来  抱抱
Come here, hon. Give me a hug.
你来这干什么
So, what are you doing here?
为一家杂志写游记
I'm writing a travel article for a magazine.
你好  我是勒西·福格蒂
Hi. Lexi Fogarty.
你好
Hi.
我和她以前是死党中的死党
Melinda and I were best friends for, like, ever.
对吧  梅格斯
Right, Migs?
我和安德里亚一起开的店
Andrea co-owns the store with me.
是的  幸会
Yeah. It's nice to meet you.
我
Wow. I...
我好想和你叙叙旧  梅格斯
I have so much I want to say to you, Migs.
我知道过去有些不愉快  但是
I know we left things a little bumpy, but...
一起吃午饭怎么样
Hey, can I take you to lunch?
不行  亚历西斯
Oh, I can't, Alexis.
我很忙
I'm very busy right now.
要不这样
Tell you what.
我这周都在这  联系我
I'll be here all weekend, so give me a call.
这是我的手机号
Here's my cell phone number.
再见
Bye.
怎么回事
Whoa. What was that?
怎么了
What?
你对那个女孩如此冷淡
You just totally iced that girl.
我没有
No, I did not.
梅林达  我都快被你的寒意冻伤了
Melinda, I have like freezer burn over here.
我们以前是死党  现在不是了
Okay, we used to be best friends and we're not any more.
了解
I got that.
怎么回事
What happened?
就是分道扬镳了
We just drifted apart.
你怎么来了
What brings you here?
给你送午饭
Bringing you lunch.
怎么了  支票跳票了
Well, what happened? A cheque bounce?
才怪  给我丈夫送个饭不行吗
No. Just felt like feeding my husband.
顺道看看你怎么样了
And, you know, seeing how you're doing...
我没事  我知道怎么回事了
You know, I'm fine. I think actually, I figured it out.
-是吗  -是的
- You did? - Yeah.
五年前的这周  我爸过世了
My dad died this week, five years ago.
每年此时  我都会感觉有点沮丧
You know, about this time I always start to go into a kind of funk.
只是  今年我把这事忘了
I think the only difference is this year I forgot,
可能为此有点闹心
so, you know, maybe it's just been weighing on me
我甚至都没注意到
and I didn't even notice it.
好吧  你现在好些了吗
Okay, so you're feeling better now?
是的  当然
Yeah, absolutely.
-你确定  -是的
- You sure then? - Yeah.
你多虑了
You worry too much.
这应该担心  我去工作了
I worry just enough. I'm going to work.
好的
All right.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- Love you. - Love you back.
请注意  标准护理教学录像
Attention. A mandatory training video on standard care
将于11:30上映
will be shown at 11:30.
全员均需按时参加
All personnel are required to attend.
女士  我在找我的马车和车夫
Young lady, I'm looking for my carriage and driver.
-你看到他们了吗  -抱歉  没有
- Have you seen them? - No. Sorry.
天啊  剧院已经关了很久了
Good Lord. The theatre's been out for ages.
我怎么和妻子说去
What will I tell my wife?
我只瞥了他一眼
I only saw him for a second,
就把我吓得要死
but this guy scared the hell out of me.
我可不是胆小的人
And I don't scare that easy.
算了吧  我们一起看《午夜凶铃》
Please. We saw The Ring together.
你还躲在沙发下不敢看呢
You spent the whole movie under your seat.
那是科幻  这是现实
That was fiction. This is real life.
我阅鬼无数  唯独这个让我窒息
I've seen a lot of ghosts. This guy made my blood run cold.
靠近他就像走进了无尽的邪恶
It was like the evils of the universe were just seeping out of him.
你觉得是有鬼魂缠着吉姆不放
And you think one of these things has attached itself to Jim?
是的  他寝食难安
Well, it makes sense. He's moody. He's not eating.
深感绝望
He has these waves of despair.
他以前不是这样的
I mean, nothing like this has ever happened to him.
就算你的假设成立
So, assuming you're right,
你要怎么摆脱此等恶鬼
what do you do to get rid of a malevolent spirit?
不知道  我祖母没教过我
I don't know. My grandmother never walked me through this one.
梅林达  一点也不安慰
Melinda, not comforting.
知道吗  该开门营业了
You know what? It's time to open.
你慢慢画  不用急
You finish up. No hurry.
以下情况下  需施行心肺复苏
Be prepared to provide resuscitation
病人呼吸停止
if the patient stops breathing
或者心脏停跳
or experiences sudden cardiac arrest.
条件允许  可携带自动除颤器
So when available, bring an automated external defibrillator
前往病人所在地
to the patient's location.
作为专业的医护人员  应当具备
A professional medical-care provider should evaluate anyone
评估病人是否患有心脏病的能力
suspected of experiencing a heart problem.
吉姆  救我  儿子
Jim. Help me, Son.
求你了  吉姆
Please, Jim!
求你了
Please!
吉姆  救我  儿子
Jim. Help me, Son.
求你了  救我
Please. Help.
求你了  吉姆
Please, Jim.
吉姆
Jim?
在这
In here.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
他们说把你送回家了
They told me you were sent home.
我看到我爸了  梅林达
I saw my dad, Mel.
在枯燥的教学影片里
In this stupid training film.
刚开始不是他  但后来明显是
I mean, it wasn't him at first, but then it was clearly him.
他向我大声呼救  究竟怎么回事
And he's yelling for me to help him. What is going on?
我想我错了
I think I was wrong.
有个灵魂一直缠着你
There is a spirit attached to you and...
-可你谁也没看到啊  -不  现在没有
- But you didn't see one. - Well, no. Not now.
但今早在消防队旁看到一个
But I saw someone at the firehouse this morning
把我吓坏了
and he really scared me.
他长得什么样
What did he look like?
平头  黑眼睛
Shaved-down hair, dark eyes,
满身的纹身
and completely covered in tattoos.
梅林达  他是在翻车事故中死去的病人
Mel, it's the patient who died when we flipped the rig,
我们的车爆胎了  记得吗
when we blew the tyre, remember?
想回家谋杀妻子的那个
That guy who was on his way to kill his wife?
他想干什么
What does he want?
难怪他会缠着你
No wonder he attached himself to you.
你是他死前见的最后一个人
You're the last person that he saw as he died.
他要我为他的死负责  要复仇吗
Does he blame me for his death? Does he want revenge?
我不知道
I don't know.
至少我没疯
At least I'm not crazy.
我们会解决的  好吗
We're gonna figure this out, all right?
我会像胶水一样粘着你
And I'm gonna stick to you like glue
等这个鬼魂出现
until I see this ghost again.
伙计们
Hey, Guys.
一切还好吗
Everything okay?
是的  很好
Yeah. Everything's fine.
怎么了
Why?
没什么
No reason.
我只是来修理柜子
You know, I just came to fix the cabinet.
谢了  吉姆  我们快被这逼疯了
Thanks, Jim. 'Cause it's driving us crazy.
天啊  怎么了
God. What happened?
你走得这么匆忙
You ran out of here so fast.
吉姆发生了一点小插曲
Jim had some kind of an episode.
以为他看到死去的父亲了
Thought he saw his dead father.
吉姆能看到鬼魂
Jim is seeing ghosts?
不  我觉得是那鬼魂
No. No. I just think the spirit, or whatever it is,
在干扰他的思想
is messing with his head.
太恐怖了
Creepy.
你准备怎么做
What are you gonna do?
除了等  别无他法
There's nothing I can do except wait until I see the ghost.
所以才带他来
You know, that's why he's here.
没什么
Nothing.
要不我们走吧  我不想吓着你
Do you want us to go? 'Cause I don't wanna freak you out.
不  没关系
No. Of course not.
在你俩身边  有一两个恶鬼算什么
What's a malevolent spirit or two between friends, right?
那是从哪来的
Where did those come from?
很漂亮吧  勒西带回来的
Aren't they pretty? Lexi brought them by.
她真的很想跟你和好
She is really trying to reach out to you.
我不知道你们为什么会闹翻
I mean, I don't know why you guys drifted apart, but...
好吧  我说谎了  我们没有闹翻
Okay, I lied. We didn't drift.
更像是玉石俱焚
It was more like crash and burn.
能谈谈吗
You wanna talk about it?
大一那年
Freshman year college.
勒西把我的能力告诉了别人
Lexi, she started telling people about my abilities.
在我知道之前
And before I knew it,
我早就成了一个笑柄
I had become some kind of laughingstock.
我忿然离开了学校
It got so uncomfortable, I finally left school.
梅林达
Melinda.
可笑的是  我心底还希望跟她
You know, the funny thing is, there's a part of me that wishes
是朋友
Alexis and I were still friends.
不  你开玩笑吧
No! Are you kidding me?
你不要再搭理她了
You can never, ever speak to her again.
永远都不要
Never, ever.
-有发现吗  -没有
- Anything?  - No.
缠身不是应该缠着不放的吗
I thought attached meant attached.
来了又走算什么
Why do they come and go?
他们侵蚀我们的精力和感情
They feed off our energy, off our emotions.
就像给他们充电一样
It's like recharging their batteries, you know?
然后就能四处游荡
And then they're free to wander off for a while.
那他们会游荡回来吗
Well, do they ever wander off and never come back?
我不清楚
Not that I know of.
就知道你会这么说
I thought you were gonna say that.
你冻坏了 抱歉
You're chilly. I'm sorry.
我去开电热器
I'll turn on the space heater.
好的
Yeah.
保险丝烧断了
I blew a fuse.
是吗  那就回床上吧
Really? Well, why don't you come back to bed
明天再修吧
and we'll fix it tomorrow?
为什么  亲爱的
Why, honey?
你害黑吗
You're afraid, are you now?
不  不是
No, I'm not scared.
但我要和你一起去
I'm gonna come with you, though.
只是烧了保险丝  电路超负荷了
I just blew a fuse, you know. I overloaded the circuit.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
蜡烛要吗
Candle?
你留着吧
You keep it.
你到了吗
Are you there now?
还没  我还在摸着去地下室
Not yet. I'm just feeling my way down to the basement.
帮个忙  能把电热器关掉吗
You wanna do me a favour? Can you unplug the space heater?
好的
Okay.
我能看到你
I can see you.
你吓不倒我的
And you don't scare me. You don't.
你是谁  你对我丈夫有何企图
Who are you? And what do you want with my husband?
我找的不是你丈夫
It's not your husband I want.
是你
It's you.
我
Me?
你找我干什么
What do you want with me?
我需要帮助
I need help.
你能看见我们
You see us.
所有亡灵
All the lost souls.
我从你身上感受到一股邪气
I feel very dark things coming from you.
如果不了解情况  我无法帮你
I can't help you if I don't understand what I'm feeling.
我杀了个人
I killed a man.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
朱利安·博基亚
Julian Borgia.
我不会装好人
I don't pretend to be a good man.
你杀了什么人
Who did you kill?
一个无辜者
Someone innocent.
我们刚抢劫完
We had just pulled a robbery
正准备逃跑
and we were trying to get away.
快滚出车子
Get out of the car!
好的  好的
Okay. All right.
我不是有意的
I didn't mean for it to happen.
很多事  我并非有意为之
There are a lot of things I never meant to do.
快走
Go! Come on!
我的同伙被捕了  但我没有
My partners were arrested, but I ran.
我知道我妻子搬走了
I knew my wife had moved away,
但我还是找到了她
but I managed to find her.
我见到了我的孩子  约瑟
I saw my child, Joseph.
一个陌生的儿子
The son that I never knew.
我以为一家三口可以重新开始
And I thought maybe that the three of us could start over.
但瑞秋早已不再爱我
But l'd lost Rachel's love a long time ago.
她不想让我见孩子
She didn't want my son exposed to me.
当晚  警察来抓我
I shouldn't have been surprised
我就知道是她告的密
when the police showed up at the house that night.
入狱之后  我开始看清真相
In prison, I started to see the truth.
我挥霍了青春
I had wasted my life.
伤及无辜
I hurt innocent people.
伤害爱我的人
And people who loved me.
我发誓出狱后
And I made a promise that when I got out,
一定要洗心革面
that I would start over clean.
出狱当天
The day I was released,
有人让我出去后帮他做点事
I was asked to do a job on the outside.
我拒绝了
I refused.
我脑海中只有一件事
My mind was on only one thing.
寻求宽恕并重新开始
To find forgiveness and to begin again.
我真的以为
I truly believed that I could do this,
可以改邪归正
that I could make amends.
然而我错了
I was wrong.
帮帮忙  我们这边需要帮手
Give us a hand. We need help in the back here.
我以为你缠着我丈夫
I think that you're haunting my husband
是因为他是你最后见到的人
because he was the last person you saw before you died.
不  是因为你
No. It's because of you.
你想再见见你的妻儿吗
Is it your wife and son? Do you wanna see them again?
不  瑞秋根本不知道我死了
No. Rachel doesn't even know I'm dead.
那我怎么帮你
Then how can I help you?
我死的那天
The day that I died,
正准备去找我错杀的那人的家人
I was going to find the family of the man that I killed
乞求他们的原谅
and I was gonna beg for forgiveness.
我现在只想完成这个心愿
I wanna see that through now.
和你一起
With you.
你愿意帮我吗
Will you help me?
我不知道该不该相信你
I don't know if I can trust you.
我听说你想伤害你妻子
I've heard that you wanted to hurt your wife.
不
No!
我没有
I never...
绝对没有
说这话的人骗了你
Whoever told you that, lied.
我爱我妻子  我从没想过要伤害她
I loved my wife. I never wanted to harm her.
我只要  求你相信我了
I just need... Would you please just believe me?
你是我最后的希望了
You're my only hope, man.
亲爱的  可以开电热器了
Honey, go ahead and plug in the space heater.
我修好电路了
I got to rewire some of the circuits...
他在这里
Is he here?
告诉我  他想怎样
Tell me what he wants.
不  告诉我你想干嘛
No, no. Tell me what you want!
对不起
I'm sorry.
这可不是个善良的灵魂
This is not a benign spirit, okay?
以我的感受来看  绝不是
Not after the stuff I've been feeling.
也许用善良形容不恰当
Okay, so maybe 'benign' was a bad word,
但他明显非常悲伤
but the man is obviously deeply unhappy,
被人误解  苟且偷生
tortured and has had a horrible life.
但不代表
That does not mean that
他心中不存丝毫善念
there's not some spark of good in him.
亲爱的  我知道你想相信
Honey, I know you wanna believe that, but this guy...
但他要我们横跨半个州
This guy wants us to drive halfway across the state
去找被他错杀的人的父母
and help him find the parents of the man he killed?
是的  我们要帮他实现
Yeah, and that's exactly what we're gonna do.
你觉得这样能有什么结果
How well do you think that is gonna go over, okay?
你告诉他们
When you tell them
你代表凶手而来吗
you represent the man who killed their son?
我知道这不简单
Well, I don't think it's gonna go over very well at all.
但不能为此而拒绝帮助他
But that is not a reason not to help him.
知道吗  你顽固得就像
You know what? You are... You are as stubborn as a...
我
Me.
我只是不想那鬼魂再缠着我
I just don't want this guy attached to me any more
或逗留在家里
or in my house.
对不起  你说得对
I'm sorry. You're right.
你别无选择
You don't have another choice.
等等我
Hey. Wait up.
你也喜欢晨跑
So you're an early-morning jogger, too?
是的
Uh, yeah.
我很喜欢这个时间段
I just love this time of day.
我和梅格斯在高中时就常一起晨跑
When Migs and I were in high school, we used to do this...
我还是想一个人晨跑
You know, I really prefer to run by myself.
谢谢
Thanks.
好吧
Okay, then.
听着
Look,
我也不想对你刻薄
I'm not trying to be a bitch.
我只是觉得
I guess I'm just one of those people
忠诚是优秀品质
who thinks that loyalty is a personal asset.
肯定因为化妆舞会的事
Oh, this is about that costume party.
天啊  我希望她能走出那个阴影
God, I wish she'd get over that.
我不知道什么化妆舞会
I don't know anything about a costume party.
那只是个玩笑
It was a joke.
几个孩子想办一场化妆舞会
Some kids decided to throw this costume party,
每人都要打扮成自己梦想中的样子
and everyone was supposed to come as their favourite fantasy.
至少她们是这么和梅林达说的
At least that's what they told Melinda.
这么说  你令她在朋友面前当众出丑
So you humiliated her in front of her friends.
我
I...
我高中时一直替她保密
I kept her secret all through high school.
她朋友里只有我参加了她祖母的葬礼
I was practically her only friend at her grandmother's funeral.
我倾听她所有的困扰
I've listened to all of her problems,
-一向如此  -亚历西斯
- all the time. - Alexis,
朋友本该如此
that's just what friends do.
真是遗憾
What a shame.
我们第一次有机会远行  却是为了这事
Our first chance to get away, look what we're doing.
这又不是什么私奔
It's not exactly a romantic getaway, huh?
他在车里吗
Is he here?
是的  他好像很入神
Yes. He seems very preoccupied.
朱利安
Julian.
我想向你道歉
Look, I just wanted to say I was sorry
事故当晚  没能把你抢救回来
for the way things went down on the night of the accident.
我当时已经死了  我并不怪他
I was already dead. I don't blame him.
他说他不怪你
He says he doesn't blame you.
谢谢  朱利安
Thanks, Julian.
现在  事实对我来说很明了
The truth is clear to me now.
这些都注定要发生
This was all meant to happen
我才能认识你
Because it led me to you.
帮我赎罪
And so to my salvation.
他说不客气
He says you're welcome.
请问是法雷尔夫人吗
Uh, Mrs. Farrell?
-是  -你好
- Yes? - Hi.
我叫梅林达·戈登  这是我丈夫吉姆
My name is Melinda Gordon. This is my husband Jim.
你不认识我们
You don't know us,
但我们最近认识了
But we've recently become acquainted with...
某个认识您儿子的人
With someone who was familiar with your son.
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
你刚才说你是谁
Who did you say you were?
梅林达·戈登
Melinda Gordon. I...
我
I...
我的妻子有一种天赋
My wife has a gift.
这很难解释
And this is going to be kind of hard to explain,
但是她能够
But she has the ability
看见并和亡者交谈
to talk to and see people who have died.
-她可以帮助他们  -稍等
- She can help them... - Wait a minute.
你是说
Are you telling me
你和我儿子有联系吗
that you've been in contact with my son?
其实  没有
Actually, no.
我和杀害他的人联系上了
I've been in contact with the man who killed him.
天呐
Oh, my God.
他并非故意伤害你儿子
He never meant to hurt your son.
是一场意外  我从来不杀人
It was an accident. I would never take a life.
他说是一场意外  还有他从不
He said that it was an accident and that he would never...
算了
It doesn't matter.
我知道我是罪人
I know I'm guilty.
因为我给他们带来这么多痛苦
You see, because I'm the cause for their pain.
他出狱后  就想来这里
He was on his way to beg you for your forgiveness
乞求你们原谅他
when he was released.
他出狱了吗
He was let out?
-怎么没通知我们  -我不知道
- Why didn't they tell us? - I don't know.
但他改变了想法
But he changed his thinking,
以及过去的生活方式
everything about the way he lived.
他想开始新的生活
He wanted to start his life over,
但事情未能如他所愿
but it didn't work out that way.
-为什么  -他被杀了
- Why not? - He was killed.
就在他前来祈求你们谅解那晚
The night he came to ask you to forgive him.
别告诉他们我的麻烦
Don't tell them about my troubles.
告诉他们  我会尽我所能
You tell them that I would give anything,
把他们的儿子带回来
anything to bring back their son.
-你还好吗  -没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
我没事  继续  跟他们讲
I'm fine. Go on. Tell them.
他希望能把你们的儿子带回来
He wishes that he could bring back your son.
够了
That's enough.
-我有一个问题  -请说
- I have one question. - Yes.
为什么我们要听他说话
Why do we have to listen to him?
为什么我们不能和儿子说话
Why can't we talk to our son?
很有可能  你们的儿子毫无牵挂地走了
Well, most likely, your son passed over easily
没有未了的心愿
without issues to keep him earthbound.
而朱利安
Julian, on the other hand,
则为自己的作为饱受煎熬
is tortured by the memory of what he did.
很好
Good.
什么
I'm sorry?
我很高兴他饱受煎熬
I'm glad he was tortured.
他知不知道
Does he have any idea
我们曾多少次希望
how many times we wished we were dead
以死来终止伤痛吗
just to stop the pain?
我们的儿子是个好孩子
He was a good boy, our son.
他关心  帮助别人
He cared. He wanted to help people.
他正准备大展宏图
He was going to build things.
出人头地
He was going to make a difference.
而那个凶手却无情杀了他
And that's who that murderer took out of the world.
他说枪杀是个意外  我相信他
I believe him when he said that the shooting was an accident.
他的枪上膛了  瞄准了
He had a loaded gun, he pointed it,
子弹脱膛  杀死了我们的儿子
it went off and killed our son.
这算什么意外
What kind of an accident is that?
他还想要宽恕
And he wants forgiveness?
要我们宽恕
From us?
休想
Never.
-你还好吗  -没事
- Are you okay? - Yeah.
头痛怎么样了
How's your headache?
好些了
Better.
太可怕了
That was horrible.
我提醒过你
I warned you.
我真替法雷尔一家难过
I just feel so badly for the Farrells.
无法想象他们是怎么走过来的
I can't imagine what they went through.
你以为呢
Well, what did you expect?
他们唯一的儿子被杀了
Their only son was killed.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉  我不知道我在说什么
I'm sorry. I don't know what I'm saying.
我不清楚我是谁  他在吗
I don't know who I am. Is he here?
不在
No.
我好像被他传染了似的
I mean, it's like I'm infected with him or something.
为什么他仍要这样对我
Why is he still doing this to me?
因为他的能量很强大
Because his energy is really powerful.
但我并不认为朱利安是坏人  吉姆
But I don't think that Julian is an evil man, Jim.
至少不再是坏人了
At least not any more.
真希望法雷尔一家能听他忏悔
I just wish the Farrells could have heard him speak.
即使那样也无济于事
It wouldn't have made any difference.
我知道你看见我了
I know you see me.
你好  亚历西斯
Hello, Alexis.
你不喜欢我  对吧
You don't like me, do you?
-有关系吗  -你是对的
- Does it matter? - Look, you were right.
我不该跟别人透露梅林达的天赋
I shouldn't have told anyone about Melinda's gift.
那是大学的第一年
It was my first year at college.
我拼命想要融入圈子
I was desperately trying to fit in and...
你应该明白
You know how it is.
好吧  可能你不明白
Okay, maybe you don't know how it is,
但对我而言就是如此
but that's how it was to me.
我想说的是
What I'm trying to say is
你能不能帮我制造一个机会
I wonder if you could set up a meeting
让我和梅林达见一面
between me and Melinda.
我知道有时宽恕难求
I know it's not easy to forgive sometimes.
能否试着和她谈谈
Maybe just try to talk to her?
要点什么
What can I get you?
我要金枪鱼三文治  你要点什么
I'll have the tuna sandwich. What do you wanna order?
吉姆
Jim?
Jim.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
但也得吃啊
Well, you have to eat.
我不饿
I am not hungry.
-你感觉怎么样  -没关系
- Tell me what you're feeling. - It doesn't matter.
有关系  我可以帮你
It does matter. I can help you.
我觉得非常
I feel totally,
极其的孤单
completely alone.
这与我和谁在一起无关
It doesn't matter who I'm with.
我觉得我会一直这样
And I feel like it will always be like this.
这不是你的感受  你知道  是他的
Those are not your feelings, you know that. They're his.
太强烈了
They're strong.
我爱你
I love you
非常爱你
so much.
你知道吗
You know that?
你只需记住这点
Well, then, just focus on that.
和朱利安保持安全距离
Keep Julian at a safe distance.
他对法雷尔一家的拒绝
He just feels hopeless,
感到无望
you know, 'cause the Farrells denied him.
他觉得孤单是因为
And he feels lonely because...
我们要去找他的妻儿
We have to find his wife and son.
-不  不行  -不行
- No. We can't.  - We can't.
我对他们不抱希望
Beyond hope with them.
并非没有希望
It is not beyond hope with them.
或许他的妻子得知他的死讯后
Maybe if his wife knows that he's dead,
会改变心意
you know, she'll have a change of heart.
我妻子恨我  我不怪她
My wife hates me and I don't blame her.
我曾无数次地背叛过我妻子
I betrayed her in every way that a husband can betray a wife.
那你的儿子呢
What about your son?
我无时无刻都想他
I think about my son all the time.
可我甚至没试着去了解他
Do you know, I didn't even try to know him.
难道不值得去祈求宽恕吗
Isn't it worth a try at forgiveness?
我已失去我的儿子
I lost my son.
我根本无权向他祈求任何东西
And I don't have the right to expect anything from him, okay?
朱利安
Julian.
你要相信我  仍有希望
You have to trust me when I say that there is hope.
我帮许多灵魂度过难关
I've been through it with others.
我知道失去爱人  对生者的影响
I've seen how the loss of a loved one can affect the survivors.
但我不管你说什么
But I don't care what you say.
并不是没有希望
It is not beyond hope.
朱利安  这是你的机会
Julian, this is your chance, huh?
你要抓住
You got to take it.
朱利安  拜托
Julian, come on.
好吧
Okay.
不管事态发展如何
Hey. However this goes down,
我要你知道  我尊重你的做法
I just wanted you to know that I respect what you do.
这种使命感以及
I mean, this calling and...
-吉姆  -不是  我
- Jim... - No, I...
如果情况依然不顺
And so if this doesn't go well...
会顺利的
Hey. It's gonna go well.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
在那儿
There.
瑞秋
Rachel.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
瑞秋  你好
Rachel, hi.
我叫梅林达·戈登  这是我丈夫吉姆
My name is Melinda Gordon. This is my husband Jim.
我们能和你谈一谈吗
Can we talk to you for a few minutes?
你怎么知道我的名字
How do you know my name?
你丈夫  朱利安告诉我的
Through your husband, Julian.
那杀千刀的又犯了什么事
What has that son of a bitch done now?
他什么也没做  他
Oh, he hasn't done anything. He...
死了
Except die.
我知道这是迟早的事
I knew it would happen sooner or later.
只是早了点
I guess it's sooner.
我都说了这是馊主意
Hey, I told you this was a bad idea.
他留了些遗言给你
He has some last words to share with you.
他死的时候  你在他身边
You were with him when he died?
不  我丈夫在
No, but my husband was.
事情要复杂的多  我们可以
It's more complicated than that. Can we...
进去说吗
Can we please come in?
约瑟  我的儿子
Joseph? My son.
都
All...
都长大了
All grown up.
就一会儿
Just for a minute.
好吧  到此为止
Okay, okay, back up here.
你是说  你和朱利安对过话
You're telling me you're talking with Julian?
和他的魂魄对话吗
Like his dead ghost or something?
是的
Yes.
连我都能感觉到他的存在
Even I feel his presence.
你能感觉到他的存在
Oh, you feel his presence, yeah?
我敢说  你还有过很多不眠之夜吧
Bet you've had a few sleepless nights.
我很久以前就离开朱利安了
Look, I left Julian behind a long time ago.
我有生活  有工作  独自抚养儿子
I got a life, I got a job, I raised my son.
我知道她能感觉到我
She can feel me. I can tell.
朱利安说  你能感觉到他
Julian says that you can feel him.
我不相信鬼魂一说
I don't believe in that spirit stuff.
你相信
You did.
我们去科尼岛上找那位占卜师时
When we went to see that fortuneteller on Coney Island.
他说我们注定会结婚
You know, the one who told us that we were gonna get married?
记得科尼岛的占卜师吗
What about the fortuneteller at Coney Island?
谁告诉你的
Who told you about that?
朱利安正和我说呢
Julian's telling me about it.
他说  那是他记忆中最美好的一天
Said it's the best day he can remember.
你那天是那么得美
You were so beautiful that day.
记得吗
Remember?
别说了
Stop it.
你穿着背心裙和凉鞋
In your sundress and sandals.
凉鞋坏了  他不得不背着你
Did a sandal break? Did he have to carry you?
住口
Stop it!
你怎么知道的  这不可能
How do you know about that? You can't!
你不可能知道
You can't know that!
告诉她  我爱她
You tell her that I love her.
他爱你
He loves you.
告诉她一切
Tell her everything.
他很抱歉伤害了你
And he's sorry for the pain he caused.
告诉她  我死有余辜
Tell her that I deserved to die.
我说不出口
I can't say that.
说什么
Say what?
告诉我
Tell me.
他说  他伤害了你  死有余辜
He said that he deserved to die for hurting you.
他再也不会伤害任何人了
And he can't hurt anyone any more.
告诉她  我原谅她
And tell her that I forgive her
向警察告发我
for turning me in to the police.
告诉她  她做得对
Tell her that she did the right thing.
他说  你向警察告发他
He says you did the right thing,
是对的
turning him in to the police.
我没有告发他
I didn't turn him in.
这就是你们的目的吗  你们想让我
Is that what this is about? Are you trying to get me
承认我检举了我丈夫吗
to admit that I blew the whistle on my husband?
不  朱利安以为
No. No. Julian thought...
我才不管他怎么想
I don't care what he thought!
我告诉你
I'm telling you,
我没有告发朱利安
I didn't turn Julian in.
是我
I did.
约瑟  是你报警来抓你爸爸的
Joseph, you called the police on your father?
为什么
Why?
因为我不想让你为他难过
Because I didn't want him making you miserable.
我看不下去了  但我不知道他会死
I couldn't stand to watch any more, but I didn't know he'd die.
我只想让他离开一阵子
I just wanted him to go away for a while.
-约瑟  -别碰我
- Joseph... - Don't touch me!
他会死  全是我的错
Because of me he's dead.
这是怎么了
What's happening?
朱利安在笑
Julian's laughing.
为什么
Why?
因为告发我的人  是我儿子
Because it was my son who turned me in.
不是你  瑞秋  是我的儿子
Not you, Rachel. My son.
为了保护他妈妈
Protecting his mother.
他很高兴
He's happy
你为了保护你妈妈
that you were protecting your mother.
他在告诉你  你做得对
He's telling you you did the right thing.
知道吗  这让我想拥抱他
You know what? That makes me wanna hug him.
你撒谎
You're lying!
-不  我没有  -你能看见他吗
- No, I'm not. - You see him?
是的
Yes.
那他右耳背后有什么
Then what's behind his right ear?
-什么  -在他右耳后面
- What? - Behind his right ear!
他说为了我的出生而纹上的
He put a tattoo there that he said was for me when I was born.
是什么
What is it?
是一只白鸽
It's a white dove.
展翅翱翔
Wings outstretched.
他还说了什么
What else does he say?
他想让你成为  他希望成为的人
He wants you to become the man he was trying to be.
学会宽恕他人
To learn forgiveness.
他说记仇
He says that being unforgiving...
就像喝毒药
Is like drinking poison.
就像自己喝毒药
...is like drinking poison
还期望别人去死
and waiting for the other person to die.
问问瑞秋有没有收到我的信
Ask Rachel if she got my letters.
他想问关于信的事
He's asking about some letters.
我没有看过
I didn't open them.
我当时很生他的气
I was mad at him.
你还留着吗
Do you still have them?
他想让你们都看看
He wants you both to read them.
他说能帮助你们理解
He said it'll help you understand.
看看他们
Look at them.
我漂亮的妻儿
My beautiful wife and son.
我曾经一度拥有
I had it all, you know?
我却离弃了他们
And I just threw it away.
他很抱歉  他抛弃了你们的爱
He's sorry that he threw your love away.
他没有抛弃
He didn't throw it away.
朱利安
Julian!
就算你试过
Even though you tried.
天知道  你入狱时  我也试过
God knows, when you went to jail, I tried.
但是  该死的  我一直爱你
But, damn it, I always loved you.
他现在需要超度
He needs to cross over now.
但他必须取得你们的原谅才能走
But he can't do that until he knows that you forgive him.
我们原谅了
We do.
我们原谅他了
We do forgive him.
告诉他
And tell him
我也爱他
that I love him, too.
真希望我能为他做点什么
I wish there was something I could do.
告诉他  可以做一件事
Tell him there is something he can do.
去找我错杀的人的父母
Go to the parents of the man that I killed,
想方设法去帮助他们
find a way to befriend them.
但别告诉他们你是谁
But don't tell them who you are.
为他们做些好事
Do good things for them.
让他们的生活更轻松些
Make their lives easier.
不要像我
Make a difference.
我会告诉他的
I'll tell him.
吉姆
Jim?
他走了吗
Is he gone?
真高兴安德里亚能说服你和我共进午餐
I am so glad Andrea talked you into having this lunch with me.
其实  安德里亚让我别来
Actually, Andrea told me not to come.
什么
What?
但这个周末非常特别
But it's been an extraordinary weekend and...
我一直在思考如何宽恕他人
I've just been doing a lot of thinking about forgiveness
互相帮助
and what people do to each other.
梅格斯  你真是太好了
That is so cool of you, Migs.
现在应该可以谈谈
So then, now, I guess, would be a good time
大一那年发生的事情了
for us to talk about what happened freshman year.
梅格斯
Migs, look...
我想说
The thing...
我想说的是  别耿耿于怀了
My thing is, don't dwell, you know?
耿耿于怀
Dwell?
不管过去发生过什么
No matter what happened back then,
我完全相信你的能力
I totally, totally believe in what you can do.
其实  这也是我来的目的
In fact, it's why I'm here.
什么
What?
你还记得我的露丝阿姨吗
Do you remember my aunt Ruth?
很讨人厌  口臭
Kind of a pain in the butt, bad breath.
她就住在美景镇旁
She lived outside Grandview.
她去年夏天病了
She got sick last summer.
我陪她熬了好几周
I put in some long, hard weekends
直到她去世
with that woman toward the end,
她才答应
and she totally promised me
把那条翡翠项链留给我
she was leaving me this emerald necklace.
真翡翠啊  梅林达
Like real emerald, Melinda,
周围还镶着一圈钻石呢
with diamonds all around it and everything.
总之  她死了
Anyway, she died.
你猜怎么着  找不到项链
And guess what? No necklace.
我翻遍了整栋房子
I combed the entire house.
我见到你  我就想
So when I saw you, I thought...
怎么了
What?
我突然感觉好多了
I suddenly feel much better.
好极了
Oh. Good.
很好  我也是
Good. You know, me, too.
因为我发现
Yeah, because I realise that
跟你每天对自己的作为相比
what you did to me is nothing
你对我做的不算什么
compared to what you do to yourself every day.
这让我看清了某些东西
And it gives me some perspective, you know?
时光飞逝啊
Wow. Time has just zoomed right by.
我得走了
I got to run.
勒西  和你吃饭很愉快
This was fun, Lexi.
至于项链的事  我会
And as far as the necklace goes, well, I would...
我会继续找的
I would keep looking.